# Renfei HUANG (黄任飞)

### **Basic Information**

Renfei is currently a first-year Ph.D. student in the **Department of Computer Science and Engineering** at the **Hong Kong University of Science and Technology**. He's supervisor is Prof. QU Huamin
(<a href="http://huamin.org">http://huamin.org</a>). His research interests include Visual Analytics of Supply Chain, Cloud Computing and Distributed Systems.

Gender: Male

Phone: +86 17816859183 / +852 51489964

Email: rhuangan@ust.hk

Address: Room CYT 3007, HKUST,

Clear Water Bay, Kowloon, Hong Kong

#### Education

• Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China

• B.Eng., Computer Science and Engineering, June 2018

• GPA: 3.9 / 4.0 or 88 / 100

• Rank: Top 5%

• Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong, China

• Ph.D. Courses, Department of Computer Science and Engineering

• GPA: 4.0 (A)

# **Standard Tests**

TOEFL iBT Total: 100 R: 29 L: 24 S: 20 W: 27

• GRE Total: 320 Verbal: 151 Quantitative: 169

# Research Experiences

- June 2016 till Sept. 2017
- Research Assistant under supervision of Prof. Yunjun GAO (<a href="http://mypage.zju.edu.cn/gaoyj\_cn">http://mypage.zju.edu.cn/gaoyj\_cn</a>)
- I implemented a co-movement pattern mining algorithm on Apache Spark based on the system developed in our lab. It's capable of mining massive trajectory data of taxis with great efficiency. I was acknowledged with my contribution in the paper "Xin Ding, Lu Chen, Yunjun Gao, Christian S. Jensen, and Hujun Bao. UlTraMan: A Unified Platform for Big Trajectory Data Management and Analytics. PVLDB, 11(7): 787-799, 2018.".
- Sept. 2017 till March 2018
- Worked with Prof. Wei WANG and PhD candidate Yinghao YU at HKUST on load balancing in distributed caching systems, such as Alluxio. The paper has been accepted by SC18 as following.
- Yinghao Yu, Renfei Huang, Wei Wang, Jun Zhang, and Khaled B.
  Letaief, "SP-Cache: Load-balanced, Redundancy-free Cluster Caching
  with Selective Partition," to appear in IEEE/ACM International Conference
  for High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis
  (SC18), Dallas, TX, November, 2018.
- March 2018 till July 2018
- Internship at cpchain.io working on Blockchain technology as a core developer and associate researcher.
- Nov. 2018 till May 2019
- Worked on an extension of the paper in SC18. The paper will be published in TPDS as following.
- Yinghao Yu, Wei Wang, Renfei Huang, Jun Zhang, and Khaled B.
   Letaief, "Achieving Load-Balanced, Redundancy-Free Cluster Caching

with Selective Partition", to appear in IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems (TPDS), 2019.

- Sept. 2018 till April 2019
- Collaborated with Huawei Noah's Ark Lab on visual analytics of industry 4.0 and supply chain with Dong Sun. The paper has been accepted by IEEE VAST 2019 (TVCG Track).
- Dong Sun, Renfei Huang, Yong Wang, Yuanzhe Chen, Jia Zeng, Mingxuan Yuan, Ting-Chuen Pong, and Huamin Qu, "PlanningVis: A Visual Analytics Approach to Production Planning in Smart Factories" to appear in IEEE Visual Analytics Science and Technology (VAST), Vancouver, BC, October, 2019.

### **Awards**

- First-Class Scholarship for Elite Students in Basic Science (Top 5% in College of Computer Science, 3 times)
- Second-Class Scholarship for Outstanding Merits (Top 3 in class)
- Huawei PhD Fellowship Scheme (HPFS), 2018.